<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Lithium Theme</title>
    <link>/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Lithium Theme</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2017 21:48:51 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Syllabus</title>
      <link>/syllabus/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2017 21:48:51 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/syllabus/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;stat-385-statistics-programming-methods&#34;&gt;STAT 385: Statistics Programming Methods&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;university-of-illinois-at-urbana-champaign&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;spring-2017&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Spring 2017&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;location-and-time&#34;&gt;Location and Time&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; Noyes 161&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time:&lt;/strong&gt; Monday, Wednesday, and Friday, 3:00 PM - 3:50 PM&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;course-websites&#34;&gt;Course Websites&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Discussion Forum:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://piazza.com/illinois/spring2017/stat385/home&#34;&gt;https://piazza.com/illinois/spring2017/stat385/home&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source Code Repository:&lt;/strong&gt;  &lt;a href=&#34;http://github.com/stat385uiuc/sp17&#34;&gt;http://github.com/stat385uiuc/sp17&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;course-staff&#34;&gt;Course Staff&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;instructor&#34;&gt;Instructor&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Name:&lt;/strong&gt; Stephane Guerrier&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Email:&lt;/strong&gt; stephane@illinois.edu&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Office:&lt;/strong&gt; 117 Illini Hall&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Office Hours:&lt;/strong&gt; TBA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;teaching-assistant&#34;&gt;Teaching Assistant&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Name:&lt;/strong&gt; James Balamuta&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Email:&lt;/strong&gt; balamut2@illinois.edu&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Office:&lt;/strong&gt; 117 Illini Hall&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Office Hours:&lt;/strong&gt; TBA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;course-description&#34;&gt;Course Description&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The world is rapidly evolving to rely on data driven decisions. These decisions
come from the work a statistician or data scientist presents in his or her
reports. In order to present an analysis, the analyst needs to be able to
leverage computing resources through programming to unearth patterns and models
that exist within data sets. As a result, statisticians and data scientists must
be savvy to programming methods that are useful to the wide variety of analysis
that they will be expected to perform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the focus of the course, fundamental programming techniques and
considerations will be introduced. Students will learn one of the leading
statistical programming languages in depth and will be well positioned to easily
learn others based on general principles. With this in mind, the course provides
a framework for writing statistical algorithms through the creation of functions
and object oriented programming. Students will also create dynamic reports that
encapsulate their code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;course-objectives&#34;&gt;Course Objectives&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After completing the course, students should be able to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Analyze and discuss the meaning behind lines of code;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Construct implementations of a statistical algorithm within a statistical
computing environment;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explain fundamental computing theory as it applies within the domain of
Statistics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;course-content&#34;&gt;Course Content&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tentative subjects include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Paradigms:&lt;/strong&gt; R, C++ (using Rcpp), OpenMP, Bash, git, regex;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reproducible Research:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;knitr&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;rmarkdown&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;packrat&lt;/code&gt;;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Computing Theory:&lt;/strong&gt; Control logic, scoping logic, big O, data structures, object-oriented programming;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Algorithms:&lt;/strong&gt; SLR, MLR, ANOVA, Accept-Reject, Probability Integral Transform;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;R packages:&lt;/strong&gt; Construction of R-packages using &lt;code&gt;devtools&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;roxygen2&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;profvis&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;testthat&lt;/code&gt;;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Visualizations:&lt;/strong&gt; Exploratory Data Analysis with Base R and &lt;code&gt;ggplot2&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;textbooks&#34;&gt;Textbooks&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please note that these textbooks are legally available online for free.
If you wish to purchase a paper copy, you are more than welcome to obtain one.
However, the references throughout the course will be primarily based upon
the electronic versions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following texts will be heavily referenced:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Required:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://adv-r.had.co.nz/&#34;&gt;Advanced R Programming&lt;/a&gt; Hadley Wickham&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Required:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://r4ds.had.co.nz/&#34;&gt;R for Data Science&lt;/a&gt; Garrett Grolemund and Hadley Wickham&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Required:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.burns-stat.com/pages/Tutor/R_inferno.pdf&#34;&gt;The R Inferno&lt;/a&gt; Patrick Burns&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following textbooks are &lt;em&gt;helpful&lt;/em&gt;, but not necessary to succeed in the course:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Supplemental:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ms.unimelb.edu.au/~odj/Teaching/MAST30025/spuRs_reformatted_part1.pdf&#34;&gt;Introduction to Scientific Programming and Simulation Using R&lt;/a&gt; Owen Jones, Robert Maillardet, and Andrew Robinson&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Supplemental:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://cran.r-project.org/doc/manuals/R-intro.pdf&#34;&gt;An introduction to R&lt;/a&gt; Jeffrey Dean and Sanjay Ghemawat&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Supplemental:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://vufind.carli.illinois.edu/vf-uiu/Record/uiu_6955421&#34;&gt;The Art of R Programming&lt;/a&gt; Norman Matloff&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Supplemental:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://r-pkgs.had.co.nz/&#34;&gt;R Packages&lt;/a&gt; Hadley Wickham&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Supplemental:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/hadley/ggplot2-book&#34;&gt;ggplot2: Elegant Graphics for Data Analysis [2nd Edition - GitHub Only]&lt;/a&gt; Hadley Wickham&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;prerequisites&#34;&gt;Prerequisites&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prior to taking this course, one should have acquired the following knowledge:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://catalog.illinois.edu/courses-of-instruction/stat/&#34;&gt;STAT 200: Statistical Analysis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ability to collaborate in a group project

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Listen, provide &lt;em&gt;constructive&lt;/em&gt; dialog, contribute work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Motivation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; If you have taken a higher-level course, e.g. STAT 400 or STAT 425,
this satisfies the STAT 200 requirement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;email-policy&#34;&gt;Email Policy&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All questions related to this class should be asked on piazza except for private
issues (e.g. missing exams). Note that posting anonymous questions on
piazza is not &lt;strong&gt;allowed&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All course emails must contain in the subject line &lt;code&gt;[STAT 385]&lt;/code&gt; followed by
a description of the e-mail&amp;rsquo;s contents and should be sent from an
&lt;code&gt;@illinois.edu&lt;/code&gt; email address. Failure to adhere to this policy
will either result in:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An automated message as a reminder of this policy;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The email is ignored.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;bug-bounty-program&#34;&gt;Bug Bounty Program&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;To err is human, but to really foul things up you need a computer.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash; &lt;strong&gt;Paul R. Ehrlich&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The course staff is a &lt;em&gt;human&lt;/em&gt;. As a result, they will sometimes introduce &lt;em&gt;bugs&lt;/em&gt;
as material becomes transcribed into a computer. Though, the course staff will
try their very best to minimize the amount of &lt;em&gt;bugs&lt;/em&gt; in the course material.
If he does create a &lt;em&gt;bug&lt;/em&gt;, please let him know. Depending on the severity, you
will be compensated with:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Severe: Unintentionally, part of the code is fundamentally flawed.

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix and/or patch is &lt;em&gt;required&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reward:&lt;/strong&gt; Bug Hall of Fame and 1 E.C. point&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Medium: Logical flaws that occur during class.

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Must explain the flaw and a potential solution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reward:&lt;/strong&gt; Large candy bar of your choice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trivial: Typos and Grammar

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Minor nuisances that if corrected via a pull request will be appreciated.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reward:&lt;/strong&gt; For every 20 typos and grammar bits a large candy bar of your choice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an added plus, there are many good discussions that arise due to mistakes&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;attendence&#34;&gt;Attendence&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You are expected to attend all lectures. Each lecture will have its own
magic word that you are responsible for entering into a form link that will be
provided on piazza. In order to be eligible to receive attendance points, you
must be &lt;em&gt;in class&lt;/em&gt;, enter the magic word within 5 minutes after it is given,
and stay for entire duration of class. Periodically, checks will be performed to
verify the attendance. Students who have entered the magic word but are not
present, will fail class and will have an academic integrity
violation opened against them. Please note, every student is eligible to miss
&lt;em&gt;four&lt;/em&gt; class periods without needing to provide a reason. Any known or potential
extracurricular conflicts should be discussed in person with the instructor
during the first week of classes, or as soon as they arise. Please be proactive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The exact method that we will use to calculate attendance at the end of the
semester is given by:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-r&#34;&gt;my_attendence = function(N, N_max){
    round( min( c( 1, N/(N_max - 4) ) )*100, 2)
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;where &lt;code&gt;N&lt;/code&gt; denotes the number of times a student has attended class and &lt;code&gt;N_max&lt;/code&gt;
denotes the maximum number of classes where attendence was taken.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;exercises&#34;&gt;Exercises&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There will be &lt;em&gt;no&lt;/em&gt; formal homework assignments this semester. Instead, there
will be  &lt;strong&gt;five&lt;/strong&gt; to &lt;strong&gt;eight&lt;/strong&gt; different excerise sets that will be made
available throughout the semester that students are highly encouraged to do.
Please note, that the exercises are done without a solution key being
made available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;exams&#34;&gt;Exams&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are &lt;strong&gt;two&lt;/strong&gt; exams for this course. The first exam is a midterm that is
worth &lt;strong&gt;20%&lt;/strong&gt; and the second exam is a final exam worth &lt;strong&gt;25%&lt;/strong&gt; that takes
place at 8:00-11:00 a.m. on Monday, May 8. The midterm and final exam &lt;em&gt;may&lt;/em&gt; have
a take-home portion in addition to a traditional in class examination.
In such cases, the take-home portion would be due within 24-48 hours after the
start of the exam. The take-home portion of the exam may not be discussed with
your classmates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;group-project&#34;&gt;Group Project&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the semester, students are expected to work on a capstone project within
a group. The capstone project is meant to either showcase a newly implemented
statistical algorithms OR extend existing functions in pre-existing packages.
Examples of past group projects have included: Data Cleaning Shiny Application,
LinkedIn Connection Scrapper and Network Visualizer, and Visualization Support
for Probability Distributions. Students should choose a topic that interests
them but is reasonable to complete within the scope of the class. Due to the
amount of projects and the individual demands of each group&amp;rsquo;s project, the
course staff will only provide &lt;em&gt;advice&lt;/em&gt; &amp;ndash; not code &amp;ndash; during Office Hours.
Failure to have a working project by the time of the final presentation day
will result in a severe penalty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The groups will be created using the &lt;a href=&#34;http://info.catme.org/&#34;&gt;CATME&lt;/a&gt; system.
The use of this system is meant to create &lt;strong&gt;strong&lt;/strong&gt; groups that are able to
effectively work together. Specifically, students will be grouped together by
leadership styles, schedule availability and skill level. Each group will
have between 3 to 5 students.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are four different phases of the group project: &lt;strong&gt;Project Proposal Presentation&lt;/strong&gt;,
&lt;strong&gt;Progress Report Presentation&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Final Project Presentation&lt;/strong&gt;, and
&lt;strong&gt;Final Project Report&lt;/strong&gt;. Each of the phases is worth &lt;strong&gt;10%&lt;/strong&gt;  making the
overall project grade &lt;strong&gt;40%&lt;/strong&gt; of the course total.  At the end, students will be
asked to perform peer evaluations of group members that may influence the grades
of students who do not contribute equally to the group project. As a results,
students should view project grades as being tentative.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-proposal-presentation&#34;&gt;Project Proposal Presentation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The project proposal presentation must be &lt;strong&gt;5 - 7 minutes&lt;/strong&gt; in duration and
consist of no more than 12 slides (not including reference slides).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Within the group project proposal, students should answer the following
questions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Problem / Topic:&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What problem or topic are you addressing?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why is it interesting or important?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What evidence supports this conclusion?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Idea:&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is your idea for addressing the problem or topic?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why is it original relative to prior work?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Where did the idea come from?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Relevance:&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How does your idea match with the course’s focus on statistical programming?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Method:&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is your general plan for realizing the idea?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feasibility:&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is this project able to be completed before the end of the semester?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What steps must occur to complete the project before the end of the semester?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time Schedule and Work Division:&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is the work plan to accomplish the necessary tasks before the end of the semester?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Preliminary Work:&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What have you done or learned anything so far for the project?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References:&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provide a list of papers or items you have read to write this proposal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;progress-report-presentation&#34;&gt;Progress Report Presentation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The project progress report presentation up should describe the present status
of the project. The progress presentation must be &lt;strong&gt;5 - 7 minutes&lt;/strong&gt; in duration
and consist of no more than 12 slides. Specifically, the slides should address
the following points:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How is the project progressing?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What has been accomplished thus far?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What have you learned?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What issues have arisen?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please &lt;strong&gt;avoid&lt;/strong&gt; including code snippets. However, clear functional output is
okay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The score for the progress report is based on how much work has been completed
since the project proposal was initially submitted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;final-project-presentation&#34;&gt;Final Project Presentation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There will be 15 minutes during class that is allocated to the presentation of
your project.  Please focus on the outcomes of the project. The score is based
solely on how well the project outcomes and methods used are conveyed. There
should be no more than 12 slides (not including references) in the presentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;final-report&#34;&gt;Final Report&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please prepare the final report using the following outline:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introduction&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Related Work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Method&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Results&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discussion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conclusion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;References&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reports will be graded based upon project outcomes, the execution of methods
described, and writing quality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;software&#34;&gt;Software&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The course will use and present the &lt;strong&gt;R&lt;/strong&gt; statistical computing language as well
as different parts of C++ through &lt;a href=&#34;http://gallery.rcpp.org/&#34;&gt;Rcpp&lt;/a&gt;. The
integrated developer environment that we will use to explore &lt;em&gt;R&lt;/em&gt; is
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rstudio.com/products/rstudio/&#34;&gt;RStudio IDE&lt;/a&gt; made by
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rstudio.com&#34;&gt;RStudio Inc&lt;/a&gt;. You are free to use any language you
choose, but the course staff will only be able to provide support for &lt;strong&gt;R&lt;/strong&gt;. If
you would like to use another statistical computing environment, please alert
the instructor ASAP to discuss feasibility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;course-grades&#34;&gt;Course Grades&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Type&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Percentage&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Total Points&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Participation&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;15&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;15&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Midterm Exam&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Final Exam&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;25&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;25&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Group Project&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4 x 10&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;40&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Course Total&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;100&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;grading-scale&#34;&gt;Grading Scale&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;A+&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;A&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;A-&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;B+&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;B&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;B-&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;C+&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;C&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;C-&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;D+&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;D&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;D-&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TBD&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;96%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;93%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;90%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;86%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;83%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;80%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;76%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;73%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;70%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;66%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;63%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grades are not curved or adjusted. This is not to dishearten students, but to
let them know that their grade is based on individual effort and not on
comparative effort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;academic-integrity&#34;&gt;Academic Integrity&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The official University of Illinois policy related to academic integrity can be
found in Article 1, Part 4 of the Student Code. &lt;a href=&#34;http://studentcode.illinois.edu/article1_part4_1-402.html&#34;&gt;Section 1-402 in particular
outlines behavior which is considered an infraction of academic
integrity.&lt;/a&gt;
These sections of the Student Code will be upheld in the STAT 385 classroom.
Any violations will be dealt with in a swift, fair and strict manner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may discuss methods for completing the exercise assignments with other
students, but the execution of these methods and the preparation of the document
must be done independently. Sufficient evidence of sharing results, collaborating
on written assignments, or simply relying on internet resources will result in a
score of 0 for the assignment. There can be no discussion with other students or
collaboration of any kind on the take-home exams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To ensure that you do not violate the academic integrity policies, all code and
solutions should be prepared yourself. All code should be typed yourself,
&lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; copy and pasted. (Except for code provided in class or in the textbook.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;changes&#34;&gt;Changes&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The instructor reserves the right to make any changes he considers academically
advisable. Such changes, if any, will be announced in class. Please note that it
is your responsibility to attend the class and keep track of the proceedings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, if changes are made&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;420&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/WpE_xMRiCLE&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to STAT 385 @ UIUC</title>
      <link>/2017/01/17/welcome-to-stat-385--uiuc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2017 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/01/17/welcome-to-stat-385--uiuc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- BLOGDOWN-BODY-BEFORE

/BLOGDOWN-BODY-BEFORE --&gt;

&lt;div id=&#34;welcome&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Welcome&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Welcome to STAT 385: Statistics Programming Methods at UIUC. The following will serve as our course website. Please excuse the dust as it becomes sea worthy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;course-information&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Course Information&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://ada.fs.illinois.edu/0012Plan1.gif&#34;&gt;Noyes 161&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time:&lt;/strong&gt; Monday, Wednesday, and Friday, 3:00 PM - 3:50 PM&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;#####../content/post/2017-01-17-welcome-to-stat385_files/figure-html/noyes_map-1.png&#34; width=&#34;672&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Generated using:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;# Load ggplot2 mapping extension
library(&amp;quot;ggmap&amp;quot;)

# Capture Image from Google Maps
noyes_map = get_map(location = c(lon = -88.225840, lat = 40.108322),
                     color = &amp;quot;color&amp;quot;,
                     source = &amp;quot;google&amp;quot;,
                     maptype = &amp;quot;satellite&amp;quot;,
                     zoom = 18)

# Classroom location
pt = data.frame(lat = 40.108322, lon = -88.225840)

# Map away
ggmap(noyes_map) + geom_point(data = pt, aes(x = lon, y = lat), 
                               color = &amp;quot;red&amp;quot;, size = 5, alpha = 0.5) + 
                    xlab(&amp;quot;Longitude&amp;quot;) + ylab(&amp;quot;Latitude&amp;quot;) +
                    ggtitle(&amp;quot;Noyes Center&amp;quot;) &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;!-- BLOGDOWN-HEAD




/BLOGDOWN-HEAD --&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>